Finding Aid for William H. McNitt papers, 1968-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William H. McNitt papers 1968-1976
McNitt, William H.
851794 Aa 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan, archivist; collected materials relating to local Democratic Party politics; student papers; and photographs.
5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of William H. McNitt (donor no. 4795 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
William H. McNitt was a graduate of the University of Michigan who later became an archivist at the Bentley Historical Library and the Gerald R. Ford Presidential Library in Ann Arbor, Michigan. While still a student and early in his professional career, McNitt also volunteered as a Democratic Party precinct captain in Ann Arbor.
The McNitt papers consist of materials collected relating to his interest in, and activities with, the local Democratic Party. Included are newsletters, leaflets, campaign materials and newspaper clippings concerning state, county, and municipal politics, particularly the presidential campaigns of Eugene McCarthy in 1968 and George McGovern in 1972, Ann Arbor City Council and school board elections; the New Democratic Coalition of Michigan; the Human Rights Party; the state presidential primary in 1972; Democratic state conventions; state elections in 1968, 1970, 1972, and 1974; and the election campaign of Congressman Richard F. VanderVeen in 1974.
The collection also includes copies of student papers on topics relating to Michigan history. The titles of these papers are "The Library Extension Movement in Grand Rapids", "Journalism and the Republican Party of Michigan, 1890-1920; A Study of the Michigan Republican Newspaper Association", and "Peace and American Society: Rebecca Shelley and the Peace Movement."
Finally, there are many hundreds of photographs taken by McNitt relating to the construction of the Bentley Library and to the accessioning of the papers of Gerald R. Ford.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.). Common Council.; Mayors--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Education--Michigan.; Elections--Michigan--1968.; Elections--Michigan--1970.; Elections--Michigan--1972.; Elections--Michigan--1974.; Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Human Rights Party (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Journalists--Michigan.; Libraries--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; McCarthy, Eugene J., 1916-2005.; McGovern, George S. (George Stanley), 1922-2012; McNitt, William H.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Michigan--Politics and government--1971-1980.; Michigan Republican Newspaper Association.; New Democratic Coalition of Michigan.; Peace--Societies, etc.; Presidents--United States--Election--1968.; Presidents--United States--Election--1972.; Republican Party (Mich.); Shelley, Rebecca, 1887-1984.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1974.; United States--Politics and government--1963-1969.; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.; VanderVeen, Richard Franklin, 1922-; Washtenaw County (Mich.); World War, 1914-1918.; Public schools--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Airplanes.; Airports.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Archives.; Archives--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Bentley Historical Library.; Building dedications.; Children.; Clothing and dress--1971-1980.; Construction industry.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Grand Rapids (Mich.); Holland (Mich.); Michigan Historical Collections.; Moving and storage trade.; Parking.; Parties.; Political elections--1976.; Political parades and rallies.; Offices.; Railroad stations.; Recreation.; Rites and ceremonies.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; Washington (D.C.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Political files
  - 1968 File
    - Eugene McCarthy Presidential Campaign, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Politics (Box 1)
    - New-Democratic Coalition of Michigan (Box 1)
  - 1969 File
    - Ann Arbor Politics (Box 1)
    - New Democratic Coalition of Michigan, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Michigan Politics (Box 1)
  - 1970 File
    - Ann Arbor Politics, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Congressional Campaign, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - United States Senate Campaign (Box 1)
    - New Democratic Coalition of Michigan (Box 1)
    - Michigan Politics, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1971 File
    - City Election, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Politics, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Human Rights Party (Box 1)
    - New Democratic Coalition of Michigan (Box 1)
    - Michigan Politics (Box 1)
    - Harold Hughes Presidential Campaign (Box 1)
    - George McGovern Presidential Campaign (Box 1)
  - 1972 File
    - City Election, 5 folders; 3 volumes scrapbook (Box 1)
    - School Board Election (Box 2)
    - Ann Arbor Politics, 4 folders; 2 volumes scrapbook (Box 2)
    - Human Rights Party, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - County Commissioner Campaigns, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - County-Wide Campaigns, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - State Representative Campaign, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Congressional Campaign, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - U.S. Senate Campaign (Box 2)
    - Statewide Campaigns, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Michigan Politics, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Presidential Primary, 6 folders (Box 2)
    - George McGovern Presidential Campaign, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - 1973 File
    - City Election, 11 folders (Box 2)
    - City Election, 1 volumes scrapbook (Box 3)
    - School Board Election, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Ann Arbor Politics, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - Human Rights Party, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - State Representative Perry Bullard, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Democratic State Convention, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - 1974 File
    - City Election, 9 folders (Box 3)
    - School Board Election (Box 3)
    - Ann Arbor Politics, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Human Rights Party, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - District Judge Campaigns (Box 3)
    - County Commissioner Campaigns, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - State Representative Perry Bullard, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - State Representative Campaign-53rd District (Box 3)
    - State Representative Campaign-52nd District (Box 3)
    - State Senate Campaign, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Congressional Campaign, 5 folders (Box 3)
    - Democratic County Conventions (Box 4)
    - Democratic State Conventions, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Democratic State Convention education post nominations, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Michigan Politics, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - February Special Election in the Fifth Congressional District, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - November Re-election Campaign of Congressman Richard VanderVeen in the Fifth Congressional District, 4 folders (Box 4)
- Research materials and student papers
  - Research notecards compiled on Ann Arbor history 1880-1899 used in preparation of chapter in Pictorial History of Ann Arbor (Box 4)
  - Student research papers
    - 1969
      - "The Michigan Progressives as a Faction and a Party" (Box 4)
      - "The Michigan Presidential Preference Primary 1912-1931" (Box 4)
    - 1970
      - "Journalism and the Republican Party of Michigan 1890-1920 A Study of the Michigan Republican Newspaper Association" (Box 4)
      - "Peace and American Society: Rebecca Shelley and the Peace Movement" (Box 4)
      - "The Library Extension Movement in Grand Rapids" (Box 4)
- Photographs
  - Photographs August 1973-December 1976, 1400 photographs approximate (Box 5)
    (Topics include Bentley Library Construction, especially the erection of stacks; move of materials into the Bentley Library; dedication of building and individual rooms; trip to Washington to get Ford Papers; installation of courtyard sculpture; staff parties; Gerald R. Ford campaign trips, May 1976 and November 1976)